### **AMISHATHAKKAR**

801 N Federal Street,1048 Chandler, Arizona, 85226 | 480-297-9499 | antisha.thakkar182@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/amisha-thakkar || http://www.amishathakkar.com

### **Career Summary:**

Software Development professional with 3.5 years' experience in the IT industry. I have hands-on experience on Java, AWS, MongoDB, Full Stack ßdevelopment projects. Currently I'm working as software engineer in Savvas formerly known as Pearson K12.

#### **Education:**

Master's in Computer Science Aug 2017- May 2019

Arizona State University, AZ.

**GPA: 3.83/4** 

**Skills and Abilities:** 

Languages: Java, Python, SQL, C, Shell Script, SQL, Mongo DB

Web Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, NodeJS, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, D3, Django and Rest API.

#### **Related Coursework:**

Computer Graphics, Advanced Database, Operating System, Cloud Computing, Data Mining, Assistive Technology, Foundations of Algorithms, Mobile Computing, Data Visualization.

# **Projects:**

**Infosys:** 

- Developed a cloud application with the help of AWS where we provided image recognition service to users, by using cloud resources (Amazon EC2, SQS, Auto scaling, Amazon deep learning AMI) to perform deep learning on image provided by the user's front end created using PHP. Both PHP and jar file running on my Amazon EC2 instance.
- Twitter-Review Analysis: Main aim is to provide review analysis of place, food, events etc. through charts. Used Django to provide user interface. Deployed application on Google App Engine used Big Query to store Tweets. Google Data Studio to Visualize data. Technologies: Python, Django, Google App Engine, Big Query, Google Data Studio.
- Developed a website for disabled people implementing screen reader, easy text, voice recognition etc. using NodeJS, AngularJS.

**Work Experience: (Software Engineer)** 

# INTERNSHIP- Infosys, Mysore

Jan 2015-Jun 2015 Jun 2015–May 2017

Worked in Infosys on Two Agile Projects BASF and AVNET. In BASF, my work involved development of
rest client service in turn involves dealing with java models to have business logic and involves interaction
with the database. Worked on Admin part who has all data for stock of chemical products, client's personal
information, products according to location etc.

## **Internship (Software Engineer) - AdviNOW Medical:**

Dec 2018-Apr 2019

• I worked on API development which helped transfer data taken from our company Kiosk to the database of our client websites.

### Savvas formerly known as Pearson K-12 (Associate Software Engineer):

Jul 2019-Present

- Developing and enhancing features to existing Pearson product. Developing automation code which will test, analyze and determine the efficiency of our product by considering all the positive and negative scenarios.
- Current role is giving me the opportunity to work with JavaScript and its advanced frameworks like NodeJS, Angular and ReactJS.
- I'm currently using java as programming language and also touch base frameworks like selenium, TestNG.
- As part of current role, I'm using Jenkins, gradle, bitbucket to commit, build and deploy the code.
- Develop Rest API and write automated test case when a new API is added to our product. Experience on working with MongoDB.
- I used sauce lab which is cloud based platform to run automated test cases. As part of migration from sauce lab to browserstack. I have modified the existing application framework.
- Part of my work involves running smoke test after the new features in our product are deployed. During deployment in case of any failures my work is to analyze if there is a service failure and fix it.